JEFF SHARP

Austin, TX

(512) 534-5477 jt74277@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jefftsharp/ Github: https://github.com/jt74277/Automated Tests

SUMMARY

I am a well-organized and disciplined remote Quality Assurance test professional seeking a new opportunity to help raise the level of product and process quality within a small to medium sized company. Twelve years of experience in manual, and two years of experience in automated, black box functional, exploratory, smoke, end-to-end, regression, acceptance, and usability testing on web and mobile apps, static content websites, e-commerce modules, SAAS applications, and other types of software has given me a solid understanding of test frameworks, methodologies, and philosophies. The majority of my QA experience has been in an Agile SCRUM environment. The QA testing programs I've setup at multiple companies have all led to improvements in release processes and reductions in post-release bugs. Most recently, I've been writing test automation in Ruby, rspec, and SitePrism in Capybara. I'm currently teaching myself Selenium and Python using a Pytest framework.

Relevant Technical Skills:

- Functional, exploratory, smoke, end-to-end, regression, and acceptance testing = 12 years
- Bug tracking (JIRA, Trac, Basecamp, Unfuddle, Phabricator) = 12 years
- Test script, test case, and test plan writing (TestRail, Confluence, Excel) = 10 years
- Test automation (Katalon, Capybara) = 3 years
- REST API testing = 2 years
- Github = 2 years

WORK EXPERIENCE

6/2021 to 12/2022

- ♦ Relevant Technology:
- Ruby
- rspec
- SitePrism
- Github
- CircleCI
- JIRA/Confluence
- MongoDB
- API

3/2017 to 6/2021

- ♦ Relevant Technology:
- PHP
- Drupal
- Selenium IDE
- Katalon Studio
- JIRA/Confluence

DUTCHIE Bend, OR (Telecommuting from Austin, TX)

QA Analyst II

- Performed black box, API, functional, exploratory, integration, and regression testing on internally developed ecommerce and POS systems in multiple browsers on OS X in a Ruby on Rails/Javascript environment using Agile/SCRUM methodology.
- Wrote, updated, and managed test cases in TestRail.
- Developed and maintained automated tests in Capybara using Ruby, rspec, and SitePrism and managed releases with Github and CircleCI.
- Tracked bugs and defects and managed sprint deployments using JIRA.
- Participated in all Agile ceremonies with the Engineering teams I supported.
- Wrote and maintained support documentation, test plans, and test matrices in Confluence.

UWORLD San Francisco, CA/Dallas, TX (Telecommuting from Austin, TX)

Sr. QA Analyst

- Responsible for implementing QA testing policies and procedures and creating associated documentation.
- Performed black box, API, functional, regression, and acceptance testing on internally developed websites and web apps in multiple browsers on OS X and Windows in a PHP/Drupal/Angular environment using Agile/SCRUM methodology.
- Wrote, administered, and executed automated pre and post deployment regression tests using Selenium IDE, Katalon Recorder, and Katalon Studio on a weekly basis.
- Led and managed a Jr. QA Engineer.
- Tracked bugs and defects and managed sprint deployments using JIRA.
- Assisted with JIRA administration duties.
- Participated in all Agile ceremonies.
- Wrote and maintained documentation in Confluence.
- Manually tested mobile apps on Android and iOS devices, including phones and tablets.

11/2016 to 11/2018

SNAPISOFT Boulder, CO (Telecommuting from Boulder, CO)

OA Lead, part time freelance contractor

Responsible for implementing QA testing policies and procedures and creating associated documentation in Confluence.

♦ Relevant Technology:

- Trello

- Performed black box, API, functional, regression, acceptance, and usability testing on internally
 developed websites in multiple versions of multiple browsers on OS X and Windows.
- Wrote functional specifications and requirements for development projects.
- Developed test plans and detailed test cases.
- Tracked bugs and defects using Trello.

7/2016 to 3/2017

- Selenium

- JIRA/Confluence

CLEAN ENERGY COLLECTIVE Louisville, CO (On-site)

♦ Relevant Technology:

- Performed manual and automated functional, acceptance, and regression testing of back office web applications in a PHP/.NET environment using Agile/SCRUM methodology.
- Administered and executed automated regression tests in a Selenium environment.
- Tested and verified sprint code deployments in multiple operating environments.
- Tracked bugs and defects and managed sprint deployments using JIRA.
- Responsible for the administration of all aspects of the organizational JIRA environment, including developing workflows and schemes, implementing suggested screen/field changes, and managing the various projects and user permissions and security.
- Created and maintained test plans, test cases, testing checklists, and training documentation using Confluence.

8/2013 to 9/2017

BURLY HOUSE NETWORKS Austin, TX (Telecommuting from Austin, TX)

QA Lead, part time freelance contractor

- ♦ Relevant Technology:
- Phabricator
- Responsible for implementing QA testing policies and procedures and creating associated documentation.
- Performed black box, API, functional, system, end-to-end, regression, acceptance, and usability testing on internally developed websites in multiple versions of multiple browsers on OS X and Windows.
- Wrote functional specifications, requirements for development projects, and detailed test cases.
- Tracked bugs and defects using Phabricator.
- Trained and managed a second QA Analyst and coordinated and managed their work responsibilities.

3/2013 to 3/2016

ACCELLA Baltimore, MD (Telecommuting from Lubbock, TX)

QA Lead

OA Analyst

- ♦ Relevant Technology:
- PHP/.NET
- Unfuddle
- Responsible for implementing QA testing policies and procedures and creating associated documentation.
- Performed black box, API, functional, end-to-end, regression, acceptance, load, and usability testing on mobile applications and internally developed websites in a PHP/.NET environment using Agile/SCRUM methodology.
- Manual testing of mobile apps on Android and iOS devices, including phones and tablets.
- Manual testing of websites in multiple versions of multiple browsers on OS X and various versions of Windows using VirtualBox VM's.
- Wrote functional specifications and requirements for development projects.
- Developed test plans and detailed test cases.
- Created user stories to capture features of applications from an end-user perspective.
- Tracked bugs and defects using Unfuddle.

4/2012 to 3/2013

<u>MATRIX TELECOMMUNICATIONS</u> Austin, Texas (On-site)

QA Analyst

- ♦ Relevant Technology:
- PHP/.NET
- Trac
- Basecamp
- Performed acceptance testing and data validation for a large migration project integrating multiple billing systems into a standard system in a PHP/.NET environment.
- Responsible for ensuring data is migrated and processed properly and accurately and verifying the correctness of customer billing through the new system using MySQL.
- Performed UI GUI black box testing in order to verify the applications handled the new accounts and requirements correctly.
- Tracked bugs and defects using Trac and Basecamp.

EDUCATION

Abilene Christian University, Abilene, TX BBA in Information Systems 3.2/4.0

Oklahoma City University, Tulsa, OK MBA in General Business 4.0/4.0